sixteen then I promise your break for 30
is for 27 meditation 16 by the way when
we will go through the schedule after
the break and your instructions say
Group one meditation group two
meditations then we have to split them
up okay number 16 it's very very useful
as you die to take refuge okay it's
similar to the falling down in the
airplane okay but if you can just
remember your llamas name as you go
through the red light the white light
the black the Mirage the the tidal wave
the mountains falling down okay when you
see it start the hallucinations they're
called standard hallucinations they come
to everyone who dies bugs rabbits fish
humans when you see them start start
saying your mama's name you know if you
can try to remember the second husband
if you can't just say llamas name okay
alright so that the llama rim when I
teach you that from the book it will say
just if your llamas name is on your lips
when you die you're doing okay you'll be
okay okay yeah
I would say personally okay this is just
my personal idea I believe that if you
have a good relationship with your heart
Lama and you say their name when you die
you cannot go to a lower room I would
say that okay minimum okay yeah I would
go to Lamas name as a backup and try to
get emptiness in there but you know I've
been in those situations and and you're
so scared all you can do is your lamas
near you to be honest this idea of pour
that in the moment of death
you can suddenly cancel all the all the
sixty-five years of bad deeds it's not
possible it's unlikely that you will
suddenly change at the moment of death
the habits that you've built up your
whole life it's unlikely galoop a
tradition so copper tradition don't
don't count on it okay you're gonna be
too scared you're gonna be hallucinating
heavy it's as if you're very drunk
extremely drunk or you're in the middle
of a bad dream it's the same you can't
you don't have the capacity to go Oh PO
ah yeah step number six you know it's
not gonna happen okay so take care of it
now
real power means take care of it now you
know understand emptiness now while your
mind is clear and don't wait till your
mind is to almost unclear it's been in
your whole life okay cuz you're not
gonna be able to remember anything okay